What are you talking about?
¿De qué hablas?
Mr. Shin...
Señor Shin.
Ms. Yun.
Señorita Yun.
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
Why are you here?
¿Qué haces aquí?
Stop!
¡Basta!
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
I apologize.
Discúlpeme.
Mr. Shin.
Señor Shin.
-What do you think you're doing? -You're one to talk.
- ¿Qué crees que haces? - Mira quién habla.
How could you punch him without even knowing the situation?
Lo golpeaste sin siquiera saber la situación.
"The situation"?
¿La situación?
When I walked in, he was on top of you. That's the situation I saw.
Estaba sobre ti. Esa esa fue la situación.
So what, then?
¿Qué esperabas?
Are you saying...
¿Estás diciendo
I interrupted... your romantic rendezvous?
que interrumpí tu cita romántica?
What did you say?
¿Qué dijiste?
Did I...
¿Acaso
interrupt something?
interrumpí algo?
That's not something a god who talks about dignity would say.
Eso no es algo que un dios digno discutiría.
You talked about "the situation."
Mencionaste "la situación".
Tell me.
Dime.
Did I interrupt something?
¿Interrumpí algo?
I don't want to explain.
No quiero explicarlo.
Are you saying I can think whatever I want?
¿Dejarás que piense lo que quiera?
Why are we even having this conversation?
¿Por qué estamos hablando de esto?
Are we...
¿Qué…?
What are we?
¿Qué somos?
Gosh, was that So-a? Why was she here?
Cielos, ¿por qué soñé que So-a estaba aquí?
She should've actually come by.
Debería haber venido de verdad.
What did she do here?
¿Qué hacía aquí?
And who was she with?
¿Y con quién estaba?
Even Sigmund Freud wouldn't be able to interpret this.
Ni Sigmund Freud podría interpretar esto.
So-a?
¿So-a?
She really is here.
En verdad vino.
Did you come alone?
¿Viniste sola?
What happened?
¿Qué pasó?
Why did you get soaked in the rain?
¿Por qué estás toda empapada?
Is something wrong?
¿Pasa algo?
Can I sleep at your place tonight?
¿Puedo quedarme en tu casa?
What? Why?
¿Qué?
I...
No puedo…
can't go home.
No puedo ir a casa.
What happened?
¿Qué pasó?
Is it done now? It's done.
¿Ya está listo? Ya está.
Did you have a bad dream?
¿Tuviste una pesadilla?
What made you contact me?
¿Por qué me contactaste?
Did something happen?
¿Pasó algo?
Was Biryeom here again?
¿Biryeom vino de nuevo?
No.
No.
You told me that...
Me dijiste que no elegí
I didn't choose to be born with such powers.
nacer con estos poderes.
You said it's not my fault.
Me dijiste que no es mi culpa.
Do you remember that?
¿Lo recuerdas?
Yes.
Sí.
Is it really not my fault?
¿De verdad no es mi culpa?
What are you talking about?
¿De qué estás hablando?
Didn't you just say that...
¿No dijiste eso
because you were afraid of me?
solo porque me tenías miedo?
If it wasn't my fault,
Si no fue mi culpa,
then who is responsible...
¿entonces quién es
for all the deaths that I caused back then?
el responsable de todas las muertes que causé?
You told me over and over again that I didn't kill them.
Me dijiste una y otra vez que no los maté.
I believed that.
Y yo te creí.
But then who is responsible for their deaths?
Pero ¿quién es el responsable?
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
Ever since they showed up,
Desde que aparecieron,
I've been losing my confidence.
perdí mi confianza.
I had forgotten...
Había olvidado
who I once used to be,
la persona que solía ser,
but it's becoming clearer and clearer these days.
pero cada día es más claro.
It's all meaningless.
No te preocupes por eso.
Yesterday,
Ayer,
I nearly killed that girl.
casi maté a esa chica.
BLESSED MENTAL HEALTH
SANTA SALUD MENTAL
Why is the door open?
¿Por qué está abierta la puerta?
Did she get here super early again?
¿Vino temprano de nuevo?
They say you sleep less when you get old. Why has she turned into an early riser?
Se duerme menos al envejecer. ¿Por qué está madrugando?
Why are you so early today?
¿Por qué llegaste tan temprano?
Who are you? Who...
¿Quién eres?
Hey, neighbor! It's you.
¡Vecino, eres tú!
Nurse Yu Sang-yu at Blessed Mental Health is overexcited as always.
El enfermero Yu Sang-yu, nervioso como siempre.
What are you doing here?
¿Qué haces aquí?
-I've been waiting. -For whom?
- Estaba esperando. - ¿A quién?
For anyone.
A quien sea.
How did you get in here?
¿Cómo entraste?
And where is Dr. Yun?
- ¿Y la Dra. Yun? - ¿Qué haces aquí?
Can you get us some tea?
¿Nos traes té?
Why did you follow me all the way here?
¿Por qué me seguiste?
Why do you keep appearing in my dreams? It's worrying me.
Me preocupa que sigas apareciendo en mis sueños.
Sang-yu, you're distracting me. Sit down.
Me estás distrayendo. Siéntate.
Why?
¿Por qué?
I know she met Mr. Shin last night.
Sé que vio al señor Shin anoche.
Why did her neighbor spend the night at her office?
¿Por qué su vecino pasó la noche aquí?
What are you implying?
¿Qué insinúas?
So-a was with me last night.
So-a estuvo conmigo anoche.
Exactly. The story doesn't add up.
Exacto. Su historia no cuadra.
You'll never make sense of this story.
Nunca entenderás esta historia.
She really shouldn't get involved with that guy.
No debería involucrarse con ese tipo.
Personally, I'm against it too.
Yo también digo lo mismo.
I should get going.
Debería irme.
I thought you went home.
Creí que te habías ido a casa.
I was going to, but I couldn't.
Iba a hacerlo, pero no pude.
So you waited for me?
¿Y me esperaste?
I wasn't exactly waiting for you.
No te estaba esperando exactamente.
What?
- ¿Qué? - Me quedé dormido pensando.
A way to do what?
¿Pensando en qué?
A way to get out of here.
En cómo salir de aquí.
You couldn't leave because you couldn't lock the door?
¿No podías cerrar la puerta?
The kind of people I hate the most are the irresponsible ones.
Odio a los irresponsables.
If I just took off, what would happen to the door?
Si me hubiera ido, ¿qué hubiera pasado con la puerta?
Should everyone only care about their own feelings and needs?
¿Deberían importarme solo mis necesidades?
Don't you think such an attitude might hurt or harm others?
Esa actitud podría dañar a otros.
How can you be so selfish?
¿Cómo puedes ser tan egoísta?
You should've at least given me your key before you left.
Deberías haberme dado tu llave.
If you're sorry, I'll let it go.
Si lo sientes, lo olvidaré.
Thank you.
Gracias.
Let's go.
Vamos.
Can I be irresponsible?
¿Puedo ser irresponsable?
If I become irresponsible...
Si me vuelvo irresponsable…
In the end, I'll have no choice but to be irresponsible.
Al final, esa será mi única opción.
So would it be okay to begin?
¿Así que puedo empezar?
You asked me what we are.
Me preguntaste qué éramos.
I've come to hope...
He llegado a esperar
that you'll always be untouched and unharmed by misfortune.
que nunca te ocurran desgracias.
You're not some distant sound that will fade away.
No eres un sonido lejano que desaparecerá.
I'm saying you're not an insignificant, fleeting matter.
No eres algo insignificante y efímero.
That is how I've come to think of you.
Eso he llegado a pensar de ti.
I want to hold you in my arms...
Quiero abrazarte
and kiss you.
y besarte.
I want you to be my first and last.
Quiero que seas mi primera y mi última.
I want my mind to be filled with thoughts of you.
Quiero pensar en ti todo el tiempo.
And when they overflow, I want to just leave them be.
Y, cuando sea demasiado, seguir pensando en ti.
I want my jealousy to be justified,
Quiero que mis celos estén justificados,
and I don't want to feel guilty, even after punching someone.
y no sentirme culpable si golpeo a alguien.
But to do all of that,
Pero para hacer todo eso,
I must begin.
debo empezar.
Like you said,
Como dijiste,
the future that is laid out in front of us won't change,
el futuro que nos espera no cambiará,
but may I still...
pero ¿podría…
begin?
…empezar de todas formas?
No.
No.
You may not.
No puedes.
Don't begin anything.
No empieces nada.
Good morning.
Buenos días.
When did you get back?
- ¿Cuándo volviste? - A veces envidio a los humanos.
I drank so much until the break of dawn,
Bebí mucho hasta el amanecer,
but I was completely sober on my way back here,
pero ya estaba sobrio al volver, lo cual fue un poco vergonzoso.
I want to know what it feels like to be drunk.
Quiero saber cómo es estar ebrio.
You see,
Los humanos
humans are such weak, inferior creatures.
son criaturas tan débiles e inferiores.
How can they lack so many things?
Carecen de tanto.
But you know what? I envy that.
Pero envidio eso.
Look at this.
Mira esto.
Things like this don't even impress you.
Esto ni siquiera te impresiona.
Because you don't lack anything,
Como no careces de nada, no puedo ofrecerte nada.
Shall I delete all the mean comments about you?
¿Borro tus malos comentarios?
By the way, I'm having a hard time getting used to seeing you
Por cierto, me cuesta acostumbrarme a verte aquí todas las mañanas.
You do everything Habaek tells you to do.
Haces lo que Habaek te dice.
You're free today, right?
Hoy estás libre, ¿no?
What are you going to do all day?
¿Tienes planes?
I'm going to watch you.
Te voy a vigilar.
That won't be easy.
Eso no será fácil.
-Hey, look. -What is it?
- Mira. - ¿Qué?
-Isn't she Hye-ra? -My gosh!
- ¿Es Hye-ra? - ¡Cielos!
Excuse me.
Disculpa.
Let's go.
Vamos.
NO PHOTOS FOUND
FOTOS ELIMINADAS
What just happened?
¿Qué pasó?
-It's Hye-ra. -Hye-ra.
Es Hye-ra.
Does he provoke you like this too?
¿También te provoca así?
By the way, why do you never talk?
Por cierto, ¿por qué nunca hablas?
Did I actually freeze and crush your tongue?
¿En verdad te congelé la lengua?
You know that I've been very patient today, right?
Fui muy paciente hoy.
I think I deserve a little reward for it, so tell me.
Me merezco que me cuentes
Why do you seem so anxious these days?
por qué estás tan ansioso últimamente.
I'm having so much fun keeping you all curious.
Me divierte que tengas curiosidad.
Even if I end up telling everyone in the world,
Aunque se lo diga a todo el mundo,
I'll never tell you.
nunca te lo contaré.
Fine.
Está bien.
Then what is it that you want from Mr. Shin?
Entonces, ¿qué quieres del señor Shin?
Tell me that, at least.
Dime eso al menos.
Answer me. What do you want from him?
Contéstame. ¿Qué quieres de él?
I want him to die.
Quiero que muera.
Mr. Kim, please cancel everything on my schedule.
Señor Kim, cancele todo en mi agenda.
I have to take care of something.
Debo encargarme de algo.
Then compensate them for all damages.
Pues compénselos por los daños.
What?
¿Qué?
Go find a job elsewhere if that's what you want to do.
Busque otro trabajo si quiere.
You're going to clear your schedule and keep following me around?
¿Cancelaste todo para poder seguirme?
I'm going to watch your every single move from this moment on.
Desde ahora, vigilaré cada paso que des.
All right. Then I'll forget about that guy, just for today.
Entonces me olvidaré de él solo por hoy.
How about you just tell her everything and ask her for help?
¿Y si le cuentas todo y le pides ayuda?
What? Help with what?
¿Qué?
You said you think she saw your wound disappear.
¿No dijiste que vio desaparecer tu herida?
I'm not sure, though.
No estoy seguro.
Sure or not, there's no reason for you to hide it.
Como sea, no hay razón para ocultarlo.
I've told you before.
Como te dije antes,
She'll be able to understand you better than anyone else can.
ella podrá entenderte mejor que nadie.
Come in.
Adelante.
I didn't know you'd be here today.
No sabía que vendría hoy.
What is happening?
¿Qué está pasando?
About that psychiatrist...
Sobre esa psiquiatra…
Are you going to marry her?
¿Te casarás con ella?
What do you mean?
¿A qué se refiere?
Does she have some major dirt on you or something?
¿Sabe algún secreto tuyo o algo así?
I just don't get it.
Simplemente no lo entiendo.
You're not the type to make such an irresponsible decision.
No sueles tomar decisiones tan irresponsables.
We'll go with the site in Chungcheong Province.
Usaremos el terreno de Chungcheong.
The assessment results show it's as good as the Gangwon Province site.
Tiene la misma calidad que el de Gangwon.
Our partners in the UK are also positive about it.
Los socios del Reino Unido concuerdan.
But I don't own any land in that province!
Pero ¡no tengo terrenos ahí!
What I'm trying to say is...
Lo que intento decir…
I came here because I was just worried that you might be in some kind of trouble.
…es que vine porque me preocupaba que estuvieras en problemas.
Your mother took you in
Tu madre te acogió
and raised you with so much love.
y te crió con tanto amor.
When you started living with us...
Cuando empezaste a vivir con nosotros…
I have to step out for a meeting.
Tengo una reunión.
Well...
Bueno.
All right.
Está bien.
In any case,
Como sea,
I think Gangwon Province will be a lot better than Chungcheong Province.
creo que Gangwon sería mucho mejor que Chungcheong.
Call me after you give it some thought.
Llámame después de pensarlo.
I won't change my mind.
No cambiaré de opinión.
Mr. Min wasn't in his office earlier.
- El señor Min no estaba en su oficina. - Aquí estoy.
Keep it brief, please.
Que sea breve, por favor.
I'm leaving early. Time is money for me right now.
No tengo mucho tiempo.
-I'll give you that money. -Two minutes have passed.
- Te compensaré. - Van dos minutos.
He's been making it so obvious since hugging me.
- Es muy obvio desde el abrazo. - ¿Cómo?
Mr. Shin is acting all cold toward me,
El Sr. Shin está actuando muy frío conmigo. No es normal.
Should I just let him know...
¿Debería decirle
that he can treat me like he used to?
que puede tratarme como antes?
-Or should I not say anything? -Don't say anything.
- ¿O no le digo nada? - No le digas nada.
That'd probably be better for your mental health.
Eso sería mejor para tu salud mental.
No.
No.
You may not.
No puedes.
Don't begin.
No empieces nada.
She turned me down.
Me rechazó.
A female human turned me down for the first time in 2,800 years.
Una humana me rechazó por primera vez en 2800 años.
Does she even realize who she just dared to turn down?
¿Comprende a quién se atrevió a rechazar?
She wasn't just foolish, arrogant,
No solo fue tonta, arrogante,
oblivious, and condescending.
inconsciente y condescendiente.
She's a coward as well.
También fue cobarde.
What's up? Why did you call me?
¿Qué tal? ¿Por qué me llamas?
He wants to lose control and go wild. That's my specialty.
Quiere olvidar las penas. Esa es mi especialidad.
That prick, he's finally growing on me.
Me está cayendo bien ese tonto.
I'll teach him 101 ways to do just that.
Le enseñaré mil formas de pasarlo bien.
What is going on?
¿Qué está pasando?
I mean, why? Why does he want to lose control and go wild?
¿Por qué querría hacer eso?
You don't have to come.
No quiere que vayas o te hubiera llamado a ti.
He called me even though he's not exactly fond of me.
Me llamó a mí aunque no le agrade.
Exactly. That's why this is so strange.
Exactamente por eso es tan extraño.
It's because I'm a guy.
Me llamó a mí porque soy hombre.
Had Judong been around, he would've called him instead.
Si Judong estuviera aquí,
In other words, I'm just Judong's substitute.
no estaría yendo como su reemplazo.
-What do you mean? -He needs some guy time.
¿A qué te refieres?
I'll find out what happened, okay?
Averiguaré qué sucedió, ¿está bien?
Practice those kissing scenes.
Practica las escenas de besos
It'd be crazy for Aphrodite to turn into Amazoness because she can't kiss.
o Afrodita se convertirá en una amazona por no saber besar.
Go to the powder room. I've prepared everything you need.
Preparé todo lo que necesitas en el tocador.
No one else would do this for you.
Nadie más haría eso por ti.
It'll be just you and Habaek, right?
Serán solo tú y Habaek, ¿cierto?
Tell me that you won't do anything bad.
¿Te portarás bien?
-I should watch both of you. -Okay, fine.
- Los iré a vigilar. - Está bien.
I heard you.
Está bien.
You know I always listen to you.
Sabes que siempre te escucho.
What are you guys going to do?
¿Qué van a hacer?
He wants to let loose and go wild like humans do,
Quiere divertirse como los humanos,
so I'll teach him the fastest and most effective way to do just that.
así que le enseñaré la forma más rápida y efectiva de hacerlo.
It wouldn't work for me, but it might for Habaek.
No funciona conmigo, pero quizá sí con Habaek.
The powder room?
¿En el tocador?
Welcome. Are you surprised?
Bienvenida. ¿Estás sorprendida?
-Welcome. Are you surprised? -I will kill you.
- Bienvenida. ¿Estás sorprendida? - Te mataré.
Welcome. Are you surprised?
Bienvenida. ¿Estás sorprendida?
I rushed to buy this place, just for you.
Compré este lugar para ti. Hace mucho que salimos.
So, is this losing control?
¿Con esto olvidaré las penas?
Not really.
No realmente.
This is just a platform.
Esto es solo una ayuda.
Once you go through this stage, you'll automatically lose control.
Cuando pases esta etapa, olvidarás todas tus penas.
I don't understand what you're talking about.
No entiendo lo que dices.
Will this make me crawl on all fours?
¿Esto me hará gatear?
Is that what you mean?
¿A eso te refieres?
That might happen too.
Eso también podría pasar.
Whatever you do, it'll be something you'd never do when you're sober,
Como sea, harás cosas que nunca harías sobrio.
so don't be too embarrassed.
No te avergüences.
By the way, why did you want to lose control and go wild today?
Por cierto, ¿por qué quieres olvidar las penas?
Why are you laughing?
¿Por qué te ríes?
I'm not sure whether or not I should hint to you that I know something.
No sé si debo decirte lo que sé.
What do you know?
¿Qué sabes?
Are things not going so well?
¿Te fue mal?
What do you mean?
¿Cómo?
I thought So-a was good for nothing,
Pensaba que So-a era una inútil,
but she somehow managed to make you blush.
pero de alguna forma logró hacerte sonrojar.
None of us would be able to do that.
Nosotros no podríamos lograr eso.
I don't know what you're talking about.
No sé de qué hablas.
Actually,
Por cierto,
do you want to hear something about her that you don't know?
¿quieres oír cosas que no sabes sobre ella?
I bet you had no idea.
Apuesto a que no tenías idea.
My friend and I have some shared memories.
Mi amiga y yo compartimos algunos recuerdos.
I know how So-a looked when she was 20, which was way before you met her.
Sé cómo lucía a los 20. Mucho antes de que la conocieras.
Is that so?
¿En serio?
She looked like freesias in spring.
Era como una flor en primavera.
She liked to wear miniskirts to show off her bare legs.
Le gustaba usar minifaldas y mostrar las piernas.
She was so bubbly.
Era tan alegre.
From what I remember, many guys had a crush on her.
Le gustaba a muchos chicos.
And she went out with a few of them.
Hasta salió con algunos de ellos.
Actually, I think she was quite close with a few of them.
De hecho, era muy cercana con algunos de ellos.
There's more.
Y en otra ocasión
She said if she took it, she would feel...
Dijo que si lo aceptaba, se sentiría en deuda conmigo
indebted to me for some odd reason.
por alguna extraña razón.
Oh, my. I should record this.
Vaya, tengo que grabar esto.
Why are you here all alone?
¿Por qué estás tan solo?
-Look at that. -Did you get turned down too?
- Miren eso. - ¿También te rechazaron?
I knew he'd discover his new self.
Sabía que descubriría su nuevo yo.
-Is she also a coward? -That dude. He outdoes me in everything.
- ¿También es una cobarde? - En verdad me supera en todo.
I admit it.
- Lo admito. - ¿Quieres que te deje solo?
I'll be off, then.
Me iré entonces.
-Why are you here all alone? -Jeez.
- ¿Por qué estás tan solo? - Cielos.
-Did you get turned down too? -He's repeating it all over again.
- ¿También te rechazaron? - Lo está repitiendo.
-Did you get rejected too? -He's too much.
- ¿Te dijeron que no? - Qué insufrible.
Is she also...
¿También es…?
Mister, what are you doing?
Oye, ¿qué estás haciendo?
What's your opinion on it?
¿Qué opinas de esto?
What are you doing?
¿Qué estás haciendo?
How dare you touch me?
¿Cómo te atreves a tocarme?
All the words I know and even the words that I don't know
Todas las palabras que conozco y hasta las que desconozco
are trapped in time by the black tongue...
quedaron congeladas para siempre en mi boca.
You look so serious.
Pero qué serio.
Can you let us in on what you're talking about?
¿Nos cuentas qué te pasó?
I'm talking about the unhappiness of all standing things.
Hablo de la infelicidad de todas las cosas vivientes.
Right, everyone is unhappy.
Cierto, nadie es feliz.
These guys are unhappy too. It's not just him.
Ellos tampoco lo son. No es solo él.
In that sense, the world is a pretty fair place.
El mundo es justo en ese sentido.
But I think you can make us happy with just a little effort.
Pero tú podrías hacernos felices de forma muy fácil.
If you could just take your wallet out of your pocket,
Si sacaras tu billetera de tu bolsillo, nos harías muy felices.
What do you say?
¿Qué dices?
They seem to be having a good time.
Parece que lo están pasando bien.
I think...
Creo que esa
that's such a stupid idea.
es una idea muy estúpida.
I hate it when someone calls me stupid.
Odio que me digan estúpido.
What?
¿Qué?
-Gosh. -What the...
Cielos.
-You piece of... -Hey, get him!
¡Acaben con él!
Today has been such an eventful day.
Pero qué día más memorable.
-How dare you! -You prick!
- ¿Cómo te atreves? - Maldito.
-Come here, you little shit. -Hey.
¡Ven aquí, imbécil!
Oh, no.
Vaya.
-Watch the legs. -He has ridiculously long legs.
- Cuidado con las piernas. - Las tiene largas.
If Mura saw this, she'd definitely freeze some tongues.
Si Mura viera esto, les congelaría las lenguas.
Hey, get his legs. Hold those legs.
Afírmale las piernas.
-Hold the legs! -Those legs...
¡Sujétalo!
-Who's this guy? -Jeez!
¿Quién es él?
Can I be irresponsible?
¿Puedo ser irresponsable?
But to do all of that,
Pero para hacer todo eso,
I must begin.
debo empezar.
Like you said,
Como dijiste
the future that is laid out in front of us won't change,
el futuro que nos espera no cambiará,
but may I still...
pero ¿podría…
begin?
…empezar de todas formas?
However much I think about it, my answer is no.
Por más que lo piense, mi respuesta es no.
Are you not calling it a day?
¿Ya te vas?
I was just about to leave.
Sí.
Sure or not, there's no reason for you to hide it.
Como sea, no hay razón para ocultarlo.
I've told you before.
Como te dije antes,
She'll be able to understand you better than anyone else can.
ella podrá entenderte mejor que nadie.
Why are you hesitating? You don't think she's worth it?
¿Acaso no crees que ella valga la pena?
It's not that.
No es eso.
She's more than worth it.
En verdad vale la pena.
She'll become the first and strongest desire I've ever had
Se convertirá en el deseo más grande que he tenido
since my life in this world began.
desde que comenzó mi vida en este mundo.
Of course I'll win her heart by fair means.
Me ganaré su corazón de manera justa.
I heard all you can do is destroy people and things.
Oí que lo único que puedes hacer es destruir.
Does someone like me deserve a woman like her?
¿Alguien como yo se merece a una mujer como ella?
Hello?
¿Aló?
Ms. Descendant, Lord Habaek isn't picking up.
Srta. Descendiente, el Sr. Habaek no contesta.
I don't think I can go home tonight.
Y como tengo turno nocturno, no podré ir hoy.
There are people who ride the duck boat this late at night?
¿Siguen usando el bote de pato a esta hora?
That shift is done,
Ya terminé ese turno,
but the owner of the fried chicken place asked me for help.
ahora estoy repartiendo pollo.
I'm getting paid more because it's a night shift.
Me pagarán más por trabajar de noche.
All right, I'll let him know.
Está bien, le avisaré.
You don't have to do this.
No es necesario que hagas esto.
Hello?
¿Aló?
Ms. Yun.
Señorita Yun.
Yes, Mr. Shin.
Sí, señor Shin.
Did I catch you...
¿La llamé en un mal momento?
Yes, we can talk.
No, para nada.
Did you get home safely last night?
¿Llegó bien a casa ayer?
Nothing happened, right?
No pasó nada, ¿cierto?
How are you feeling?
¿Cómo se siente?
I'm sorry.
Lo siento.
I should've called you first.
Debería haberlo llamado primero.
All is well.
No se preocupe.
-I'm fine. -I'm really sorry.
- Estoy bien. - Lo siento mucho.
I should've been more thoughtful as your psychiatrist.
Debí ser más considerada.
It's okay.
Está bien.
Well...
Bueno…
About that guy last night...
Sobre lo que pasó anoche…
I can't explain in detail,
No puedo explicarlo bien, pero creo que hubo un malentendido.
He asked me to tell you that he's sorry.
Me pidió que le dijera que lo siente.
I should've told you sooner.
Debí decirle antes.
I see.
Ya veo.
I'll book you in again for Monday.
Lo agendaré otra vez para el lunes.
That works for you, right?
¿Está bien?
Of course.
Claro.
Then how about we start the sessions for your employees
¿Y si empezamos con sus empleados el miércoles?
Sure, let's do that.
Sí, seguro.
Don't you have to go back to the farm soon to do more work?
¿No tiene trabajo en la granja?
I'll have to see.
Tendré que ver.
All right. You should get some rest at the weekend.
Está bien. Debería descansar este fin de semana.
You looked very tired yesterday.
Ayer se veía muy cansado.
I will.
Lo haré.
I have to go.
Tengo que irme.
Okay, I'll see you on Monday.
Bien, nos vemos el lunes.
You really don't have to do this.
En serio, no tienes que hacer esto.
Why do you work all the part-time gigs alone?
¿Por qué solo tú trabajas?
Does the water god do nothing?
¿El dios del Agua no hace nada?
Sorry? How dare you utter such a blasphemous remark?
¿Cómo te atreves a decir algo tan blasfemo?
I just thought those in your world might think differently.
Pensé que los de tu mundo pensarían diferente.
You don't have other part-time jobs?
¿No tienes otros trabajos?
I don't have a government-issued ID,
Me cuesta encontrar trabajos porque no tengo carné de identidad.
By the way, from what happened to So-a to what the beggar...
Por cierto, lo que pasó con ese mendigo…
I mean, you know how the voracious god cursed the water god,
Digo, cuando el dios voraz maldijo al dios del Agua.
a kiss is mandatory, right?
El beso es obligatorio, ¿cierto?
-Pardon? -What I'm saying is,
- ¿Qué? - Cuando los dioses usan sus poderes
There must be no other way.
Debe ser la única forma.
Well, I wasn't suggesting we do something now!
¡No estaba sugiriendo que lo hiciéramos ahora!
You sort it out yourself. You won't let me in anyway.
Te lo encargo.
Gosh, did he drink?
¿Estuvo bebiendo?
How much did he drink?
¿Cuánto bebió?
By the way, did you ever crawl on all fours when you were drunk?
Por cierto, ¿alguna vez gateaste estando borracha?
What?
¿Qué?
You didn't pole dance, did you?
¿Bailaste en la barra?
I told him that you're the innocent, ladylike type, just in case.
Por si acaso, le dije que eras una dama inocente.
I'm off.
Me voy.
What?
¿Qué?
If I must ask a favor of you...
Si te pidiera un favor,
should I ask you to make him stay
¿te pediría que hagas que se quede
or let him go?
o que se vaya?
I can't figure out how I really feel about it.
No sé cómo me siento al respecto.
What?
¿Qué?
I should book a session with you one of these days.
Debería agendar una sesión contigo.
Hold on.
Afírmate.
Wake up, please.
Despierta, por favor.
Namsuri isn't back yet.
Namsuri no ha regresado todavía.
Stay here for now.
Quédate aquí por ahora.
Wait for him here.
Espéralo aquí.
As soon as he's back,
Le diré que te lleve en cuanto vuelva.
I'm exhausted.
Estoy agotada.
Let's just stay like this.
Quedémonos así.
I won't begin...
No empezaré,
so don't be afraid.
así que no tengas miedo.
Let's just...
Solo…
stay like this for a few minutes.
…quedémonos así por unos minutos.
Why are you here all alone?
¿Por qué estás tan solo? ¿También te rechazaron?
Did you get rejected by a girl too?
¿También te dijeron que no?
Is she also a coward?
¿También es una cobarde?
It's a rare video, so I'd better keep it safe.
Es un video raro, así que cuídalo.
I can't believe he's become such a wreck.
No puedo creer que esté tan mal.
He was always a handful.
Siempre fue problemático.
He can be small-minded and petty at times.
A veces puede ser mezquino y hasta cobarde.
And to be frank, he's half-human right now.
Es mitad humano ahora.
He might even fart, you know.
Hasta puede tirarse pedos.
-You did this on purpose, didn't you? -No.
- ¿Hiciste esto a propósito? - No.
I was curious, and I've learned he really gets drunk.
Quería ver si se embriagaba. Siempre he querido experimentarlo.
He's making me jealous in all kinds of ways.
Lo envidio.
What's wrong with him?
¿Qué le pasa? ¿Qué rayos está pasando?
Tell me.
Dime.
Why the hell is he staying here instead of going back?
¿Por qué diablos no quiere regresar?
Stop worrying about him. He's just seeing what it's like.
Deja de preocuparte. Solo está experimentando.
He feels pressured because he'll ascend the throne soon.
Está estresado porque ascenderá al trono.
And once that happens,
Y cuando eso pase,
he won't be able to enjoy this kind of freedom.
ya no tendrá este tipo de libertad.
That's why he has a lot on his mind now.
Por eso está actuando así.
Really?
¿En serio?
Why did he become so weak? It doesn't suit him at all.
¿Cuándo se volvió tan débil? No suele ser así.
Does the water here not agree with him?
¿Será el agua de acá?
Should I get him some herbal medicine, the kind that humans take?
¿Y si le doy plantas medicinales como las que toman los humanos?
Why are you standing there like that?
¿Qué haces ahí?
It'll be another hot day.
Hoy también será caluroso.
Do you want a glass of the fruit juice?
¿Quieres jugo de fruta?
I noticed that there are a lot of books in this house.
Noté que tienes muchos libros.
-They're all books about traveling. -Traveling?
Son libros sobre viajes.
because I wanted to get out of this country.
porque quería irme del país.
But I haven't read that one yet.
Pero aún no leo ese.
IF THERE'S A WORD MORE POWERFUL THAN LOVE
SI HAY UNA PALABRA MÁS FUERTE QUE EL AMOR
The sun's out, so I should hang the clean laundry on the rooftop.
Salió el sol, así que colgaré la ropa arriba.
Let's eat after I finish hanging these up.
Comamos después de esto.
Can you read it out loud for me? Just the first sentence.
¿Me lees la primera oración?
Usually, the first sentence of the book
La primera oración del libro
tells me whether or not I should read the rest.
me dice si debo leer el resto.
"All humans are stars.
"Todos los humanos son estrellas.
Flowers have bloomed on every abandoned island."
Las flores florecieron en cada isla abandonada".
If a book starts like that, I can read it all night long.
Si un libro empieza así, podría leerlo toda la noche.
I asked you to read it out loud.
¿No me lo leerás?
Why are you reading it silently? You're mean.
¿Por qué lo lees en silencio?
-Don't mind me. -What?
- Ignórame. - ¿Qué?
You can't even read the first sentence aloud for me?
¿No me puedes leer la primera oración?
I'll tell you to stop reading if I don't like what I hear.
Te avisaré si no me gusta lo que escucho.
I know it's embarrassing to read something out loud.
Sé que es vergonzoso leer en voz alta.
"How...
"¿Cómo nos conocimos?
One day, a butterfly flew like a petal
Un día, una mariposa voló como un pétalo
and made a small flutter.
e hizo un leve aleteo.
How did we meet and end up here?
¿Cómo es que nos conocimos y terminamos aquí?
The corner of the street where we exchanged our love on one spring day.
La esquina donde intercambiamos nuestro amor en un día de primavera.
It was a miracle.
Fue un milagro.
We slowly held hands as we walked down the street together.
Nos tomamos de la mano mientras caminamos.
The dandelions beneath the telephone pole swayed brightly.
Los dientes de león bajo el poste se balanceaban radiantemente.
How did we manage to come this far together?
¿Cómo logramos llegar tan lejos juntos?
Were we able to reach love because we walked through
¿Alcanzamos el amor
such lovely moments together?
porque tuvimos esos momentos tan lindos juntos?
I've come to believe that there is no such thing as coincidence in love.
Creo que no existen las coincidencias en el amor.
I've come to trust that the universe calculates
Creo que el universo calcula
even the littlest things such as the wing stroke of a butterfly
hasta el más pequeño detalle, como el aleteo de una mariposa,
in order to make two people fall in love.
para enamorar a dos personas.
An inevitable miracle.
Un milagro inevitable.
I suppose I didn't want to...
Supongo que no quería pensar
think that we met by a mere coincidence.
que nos conocimos por una mera coincidencia.
So, the only thing I can do...
Así que lo único que puedo hacer
-is do my best..." -I like it.
- es dar lo mejor de mí…". - Me gustó.
You can stop reading. Let's go eat now.
Vayamos a comer.
I'll read the rest myself.
Leeré el resto sola.
Oh, boy.
Cielos.
-Is this edible? -I did my best.
¿Es comestible?
-Where's Namsuri? -He'll be here soon.
- ¿Y Namsuri? - Llegará pronto.
Is it good?
¿Está bueno?
Not really.
En realidad no.
Why did you wear miniskirts and show off your bare legs?
¿Por qué usabas minifaldas y mostrabas las piernas?
-What? -Back in the day.
- ¿Qué? - En el pasado.
I heard you used to look like freesias in springtime.
Oí que eras como una flor en primavera.
Why don't you look like that anymore?
¿Por qué ya no luces así?
I told him that you're the innocent, ladylike type, just in case.
Por si acaso, le dije que eras una dama inocente.
I also heard you dated quite a few guys.
También oí que saliste con varios tipos.
Did you always have a knack for seducing men?
¿Siempre fuiste buena seduciendo hombres?
Do you still keep in touch with them?
¿Los sigues viendo?
Excuse me.
Disculpa.
You shouldn't talk with food in your mouth.
No se habla con la boca llena.
What about you?
¿Qué hay de ti?
I'm sure you've dated countless women
Seguro saliste con muchas mujeres en los últimos 2800 años.
Who did you like the most out of all your exes?
¿Cuál es tu favorita?
Who?
¿Quién?
Tell me.
Dime.
Why are you so quiet all of a sudden? You must've liked her a lot.
¿Por qué te callaste?
-I'll pretend I'm not curious anymore. -Thanks.
- Fingiré que ya no me importa. - Gracias.
I would've repaid you if I'd had my powers.
Te recompensaría si tuviera mis poderes.
What would you have done for me?
¿Qué me darías?
You're a woman of many flaws, so I'll help you fix them.
Te ayudaría a corregir tus tantos defectos.
I'll make sure you can swim
Te enseñaría a nadar
and gulp down cold water without any problems.
y beber agua fría sin problemas.
I'll fix those things on my own.
Corregiré esas cosas sola.
Be a bit more daring since it's just your imagination anyway.
Vamos, sé un poco más osado.
What do you want?
¿Qué quieres?
-Become like Sheikh Mansour? -That'd be nice too.
- ¿Ser millonaria? - Eso sería bueno.
You can do a lot of things.
Puedes hacer muchas cosas.
First, turn my land into a gold field.
Primero, convierte a mi terreno en un campo de oro.
And please1 let oil come out of the East Sea.
Y haz que salga petróleo del mar del Este.
I'll be the owner of that oil field.
Y que yo sea la dueña.
And I'd love it if the two Koreas could become one again.
Y que las dos Coreas vuelvan a unirse.
After that, you can build a house
Y construye un templo griego en la playa de Vanuatu.
And change my looks as well if that's possible.
Y cambia mi apariencia.
I'd love to look like a tall, voluptuous Greek goddess.
Quiero lucir como una diosa griega.
Today, I'm having breakfast at the White House.
Hoy desayunaré en la Casa Blanca.
Meeting the president would be too much for me,
Ver al presidente sería mucho,
so I'll just meet the members of the shadow cabinet.
así que solo veré al gabinete.
In the afternoon, I'll fly to London on my private jet.
Por la tarde, iré a Londres,
I have to attend an opening party at the Saatchi Gallery
a la fiesta de apertura de la Galería Saatchi,
because I'm a world-famous celebrity.
porque seré una celebridad.
I have to go to New York after that.
Luego iré a Nueva York.
Jude Law wants to meet up for coffee and catch-up.
Jude Law querrá tomarse un café conmigo.
I'll go shopping in SoHo,
Iré de compras en Soho,
and I'm going to stay at the Four Seasons Hotel
y me quedaré en la suite presidencial del Four Seasons.
If I get too tired, I'll just head straight back to Vanuatu.
Si me canso, solo volveré Vanuatu.
I'll tell Jude Law that we'll have to meet next time.
Tendré que juntarme otro día con Jude Law.
That's the kind of life I want.
Esa es la vida que quiero.
What? Where did he go?
¿Qué? ¿Adónde se fue?
-What are you doing? -I couldn't really understand any of it,
- ¿Qué estás haciendo? - No entendía nada.
but it was making me cringe so much that I couldn't keep listening.
Me dio tanta vergüenza ajena que no pude seguir escuchando.
Having these human senses
Estas sensaciones humanas son bastante molestas.
A king must know
Un rey debe saber escuchar a su gente.
How about some iced coffee for dessert?
¿Qué tal un café helado de postre?
Sure.
Seguro.
Let's make ourselves a simple drink.
Hagamos trago simple.
Things would've been different if you'd had the servant's tablet.
Todo sería diferente con el amuleto del sirviente.
"The servant's tablet"?
¿El amuleto del sirviente?
The proof that my family pledged to serve the gods?
¿La prueba de que mi familia prometió servirle a los dioses?
It has the power to fulfill the servant's wish.
Puede cumplirle un deseo a un sirviente.
It's a small token of gratitude from the gods.
Es una muestra de agradecimiento de los dioses.
Then give it to me.
Pues dámelo.
I lost it.
Se me perdió.
Why bother telling me about it, then?
¿Para qué me cuentas entonces?
My ex-boyfriend also loved iced coffee.
A mi exnovio también le gustaba el café helado.
You shouldn't have lost that tablet.
No debiste haber perdido ese amuleto.
Then you could've granted me my wish.
Podrías haber concedido mi deseo.
I wouldn't have been able to understand what wish.
- Igual no lo hubiera entendido. - ¿Por qué?
It has to be a real wish.
Debe ser un deseo real.
Something that you truly want.
Uno que en verdad quieras.
-Just one wish. -Just one?
Solo uno.
From what I know, your wish isn't to become filthy rich.
Por lo que sé, tu deseo no es ser millonaria.
I'm home.
Llegué.
You're back.
Volviste.
You must be hungry. Come to the kitchen.
Debes tener hambre. Ven.
Was everything okay?
¿Todo bien?
I couldn't focus on work because I was worried,
Estaba preocupado porque estaría solo toda la noche.
-Namsuri. -Yes?
- Namsuri. - ¿Sí?
Go eat your food.
Ve a comer.
Okay.
De acuerdo.
I earned a lot of money.
Gané mucho dinero.
Tell me if there's anything you want to eat or read.
Dígame si quiere comer o leer algo.
-There's nothing. -Okay. Then I'll take care of everything.
- Estoy bien. - Bien. Me encargaré de todo.
Have a seat.
Toma asiento.
I haven't finished my meal yet.
No había terminado de comer.
-You must be exhausted. -No, I'm all right.
- Debes estar exhausto. - No, estoy bien.
But I almost engaged in some degrading behavior.
Pero casi hice algo denigrante anoche.
What a cute cup.
Qué linda taza.
Mr. Nature worked part-time and got it for me as a gift.
- El Sr. Naturaleza me la regaló. - ¿Qué?
What's wrong?
¿Qué pasa?
Did Lord Habaek really work and buy this for you himself?
¿El señor Habaek trabajó y le regaló esa taza?
Yes.
Sí.
Wait, Namsuri.
Espera, Namsuri.
What's wrong with him?
¿Qué le pasa?
It's probably because he's very tired.
Debe estar cansado.
Sleep after you eat. It won't be good when it's cold.
Come antes de que se enfríe.
Where are you going?
¿Adónde vas?
What's the matter with him?
¿Qué le pasa?
The heat must be getting to him.
Debe ser el calor.
Do you want to go to the beach?
¿Quieres ir a la playa?
What?
¿Qué?
You don't turn into a mermaid when you enter the sea, do you?
No te conviertes en sirena si entras al mar, ¿cierto?
The sea?
¿El mar?
Look up "Picnic lunch boxes" on the Internet,
Busca "almuerzo para pícnic" en internet para comprar cosas.
-You want me to do it? -You don't want to?
- ¿Quieres que cocine? - ¿Tú no?
Then we'll just take the leftover kimchi fried rice.
O podemos llevar el arroz con kimchi que sobró.
"Picnic lunch boxes."
"Almuerzo para pícnic".
So, what do we need to buy?
¿Qué compramos?
Avocados, salmon, abalone,
Aguacates, salmón, abulón,
-eel, mushrooms, and short ribs. -What's gotten into you?
anguila, hongos y costillas.
What?
¿Qué?
You said we're making lunch for a picnic.
Dijiste que haríamos un pícnic.
Exactly. People usually make gimbap when they go on a picnic.
Sí, pero la gente suele hacer gimbap.
What?
¿Qué?
Why are you upset?
¿Por qué te enojaste?
Gosh, that guy...
Cielos, este tipo…
It'll burst open in your mouth anyway.
Igual se arruinará al comerlo.
Who is this?
¿Quién es?
It's me. I'm going for lunch with Biryeom. You should join us.
Soy yo.
-I'm busy. -I saw you going all crazy last night.
- Estoy ocupado. - Vi que enloqueciste anoche.
I shouldn't leave you alone.
No debería dejarte solo.
I can't go anywhere as I have to keep an eye on Biryeom,
Como debo vigilar a Biryeom, deberías mudarte aquí.
-I'm going to the beach. -What?
- Voy a la playa. - ¿Qué?
-What did you say? -I'm making gimbap.
- ¿Qué dijiste? - Estoy haciendo gimbap.
I'll check it out first and take you there if it's nice.
Te llevaré si es agradable. ¡No eches ese gimbap roto!
I have to go.
Debo irme.
Have some class, will you?
Ten un poco de clase.
"Broken gimbap"?
¿"Gimbap roto"?
Is he not coming?
¿No va a venir?
He says he's making gimbap to go to the beach. What does that mean?
Dijo que está haciendo gimbap para ir a la playa.
What?
¿Qué?
I have to say, I'm slowly starting to grow fond of that dude.
Debo aceptar que le estoy tomando cariño.
I'll go get changed. Let's go boxing.
Iré a cambiarme. Vamos a boxear.
I can't believe this. Gimbap?
No puedo creerlo.
Has he really lost his mind or something?
¿Acaso se volvió loco?
Why are you here all alone?
¿Por qué estás tan solo?
Did you get turned down too?
¿También te rechazaron?
Did you get rejected by a girl too?
¿También te dijeron que no?
Is she also a coward?
¿También es una cobarde?
I haven't seen this one.
No había visto este.
If I could...
Si pudiera,
I'd really love to...
me encantaría
live with her.
vivir con ella.
Here in this world.
Aquí en este mundo.
Habaek!
¡Habaek!
Where did she go?
¿Adónde fue?
The person you are trying to reach is unavailable. Please leave a message.
Este número no está disponible. Deje un mensaje.
-He's not picking up? -No.
- ¿No contesta? - No.
That must be him.
Debe ser él.
Namsuri, let's go to--
Namsuri, vamos a…
What brings you here?
¿Qué te trae por aquí?
Do you know why a lowly human being like you
¿Sabes por qué una humana como tú puede hablar con nosotros?
If you find out that it was all because of your ancestor...
Si descubres lo que hizo tu ancestro…
Mura, what are you doing?
Mura, ¿qué estás haciendo?
...I wonder if you'll still be able to stay by Habaek's side.
- ¿Podrás seguir al lado de Habaek? - ¡Mura!
Shall I tell you why your ancestor ended up...
¿Te digo por qué tu ancestro se convirtió en un sirviente divino?
Stop.
Basta.
Mura!
¡Mura!
-Do whatever it takes to persuade him. -I heard you did nothing.
- Haz todo por persuadirlo. - Oí que no hiciste nada.
If he doesn't ascend the throne, he'll be nothing.
Si no asciende al trono, no será nada.
-What is it that you really want to say? -I beg you. Please don't hold him back.
- ¿Qué quieres decir? - Por favor, no lo retengas.
I bluffed that I'd protect you.
Prometí que te protegería.
I admitted in front of her that he's in love with her.
Le admití que está enamorado de ella.
Why did I make a promise that I cannot keep?
¿Por qué prometí algo que no puedo cumplir?
-I want to ask you if I can leave... -Go back.
- ¿Puedo volver? - Hazlo.
I've realized that you truly want me to leave.
Me di cuenta que quieres que me vaya.
Return to where you belong. Please go back.
Regresa a donde perteneces por favor.
Let's just part ways here.
Aquí nos separarnos.
Goodbye.
Adiós.
Farewell.
Hasta siempre.